VINCENT J. SCHAEFER PAPERS (UA902.010) 1891-1993
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- General Electric- Non-Project Cirrus, 1891-1993; 1; 21.0
  - Correspondence, 1939-1954; Undated; 1.5
    - Split Rock Lodge- Snow for Ski Facilities, 1946 December-1948 January (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - State University of New York to I. Langmuir- Langmuir's Resignation from Board of Trustees, 1949 September 12 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Stetson, Harlan T.- Letter re: Mean Hourly Discharge, 1944 May 02 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Surface Replicas: Biological Applications, 1942 October 10 (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - Surface Replicas: Botanical Applications, Undated (Box 18, Folder 45)
    - Teale, Edwin Way- Letter to Schaefer (Snowflakes), 1945 August 12 (Box 18, Folder 46)
    - Union of South Africa- Scientific Liaison Office, 1947 March-1948 January (Box 18, Folder 47)
    - Vancouver Forest Service, 1947 November-1948 July (Box 18, Folder 48)
    - Ventilation Studies, 1947 January 21 (Box 18, Folder 49)
    - Vonnegut, B. to I. Langmuir- Rain Gauge Cloth (Cloth Included), 1944 August 01 (Box 18, Folder 50)
    - Walton, Sande, High School Student, to I. Langmuir, with reply, 1974 September 22; 1947 October 14 (Box 18, Folder 51)
    - Waugh, Dr. David to I. Langmuir and K. Blodgett, 1947 February-1947 April (Box 18, Folder 52)
    - Waugh, Dr. David (MIT) from I. Langmuir, 1948 April 30 (Box 18, Folder 53)
    - Weather Control: Article for Grolier, 1951 June-1951 July (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - Wrinch, Dr. Dorothy- Oxford University, Undated (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - Yagoda, H. Article and Letter to Schaefer: "Analytical Patterns in the Study of Mineral and Biological Materials", 1943 February; 1944 April 29 (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - Younger, Dorothy- Rhyming Letter, 1946 November 28 (Box 18, Folder 57)
  - Subject Files, 1891-1978; Undated; 1.6
    The Schaefer subject files are a collection of brochures, notes, and other ephemera that have enduring value but do not belong in other categories such as cloud seeding or snow and ice research. These files include research notes from sources other than General Electric; scientists and entrepreneurs frequently exchanged results of their work with one another, but to avoid confusion, the work of Schaefer and other G.E. scientists can be found in the next subseries while informal research notes and observations by others are located here.
    - Address Book, Undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Aerial Photos, Assorted, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Aeronautical Chart for Hudson, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Air Material Command, Dayton Ohio- Temperature Distribution notes and photos, ca. 1946 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Advancing and Receding Contact- Angles, 1949-1950 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Albany Airport Instrument Approach Chart, 1951 October 04 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Amateur Weathering of America, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - American Chemical Society, Eastern New York Section, Directory and By-Laws, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - American Chemical Society- Schaefer's Enrollment for 1938, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - American Geophysical Union- Relationship with General Electric, 1945-1946; 1948; 1952 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - American Men of Science Questionnaire, ca. 1948 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - American Meteorological Society Committee on Professional Ethics and Standards-Report to the Council, 1951 May 03 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - American Meteorological Society, Meetings and Code of Ethics, 1949-1951 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - American Meteorological Society, Meeting Programs, 1946-1954; Undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - American Polar Society- Membership Invitation, Undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - American Society for Testing Materials- Poster Advertising V.J. Schaefer and P.E. Kraght Speaking Engagement, 1948 April 13 (Oversized 4, Folder 2)
    - Apprenticeship Records, 1923-1924 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Atmospheric Data from Rocket-Flights- News article and letter, 1948; 1949 January 13 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Atmospheric Motion and Particle Movement, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Biography- Bensin, Basil M., 1948 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Binaural Effect Studies, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Biography of Schaefer, Capital Cogs, 1950 September 06 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Biography of Schaefer, Manuscript, Undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Bishops Cap (Mitella sp.) photo negative, Undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - News Clipping, Award Recipient (photocopy)- Blodgett, Katherine, 1972 November 09 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Boeing Aircraft Photos, 1960; Undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Brazilian Traction, Light and Power 36th Annual Report, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - British Glaciological Society, 1947-1951 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Calgon- Formulas, Properties, Graphs, 1937; Undated (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Calrod Experiment Summary with Letter, Undated (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Candid Camera- Picture of I. Langmuir, 1944 December 29 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Cartoons and Comics, 1947-1950 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Centennial Publication: "G.E. 100-Toward the Second Century", 1978 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Character Reference for Schaefer, 1947 September 16 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - "Class Assignment" Notebook, 1934-1935 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Climatic Trends in the Northeastern U.S. Symposium, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - "Cloud Forms of the Jet Stream" articles with related photos & news clippings, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Cold Chamber: Bowser, Inc. Refrigeration Division Brochure- Temperature Altitude and Humidity Simulation Units, Undated (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Cold Chamber: Demonstration at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, Undated (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Colloid Symposium (MIT)- Program of Papers, 1938 June 09-1968 June 11 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Committee on Geophysical Science of the joint Research and Development Board- Panel on Meteorology, 1947 April 23 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Compendium of Meteorology tentative table of contents with partial letter, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Costs for Making Copies of Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - Crystallization of Metals, Rocks and Ice-Symposium, 1951 October (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - Current Science, Vol. XXVIII #4, featuring I. Langmuir, V. Schaefer, K. Blodgett, C.G. Suits, 1942 October 05-1942 October 09 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - Distribution of Contract recommendation (with note to Schaefer from "Vic", Undated (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - Dutch (?) Meteorological Map, Undated (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - Eastern Snow Conference Materials, 1950 February 16-1950 February 17; 1951 February 15-1951 February 17; 1952 February 14-1952 February 15 (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - Edison General Electric Company: Instructions to Foremen Fragile Item, 1891 (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - Einladung zur Sitzung der Naturforschenden Gesellschaft- Zurich, 1953 December (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - Electron Microscopy: Description with Letter, 1942 June 02; Undated (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - Electron Microscopy: Newspaper Clippings, 1941 November 06; 1941 November 21 (Box 19, Folder 51)
    - Electron Microscopy: Symposium, 1942 November 27 (Box 19, Folder 52)
    - Electronic Stratometer vs. Radio Sonde- Nomenclature Change from Minutes of University of Chicago Dept. of Meteorology, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 53)
    - Employee Rating Sheets instructions, 1949 July (Box 19, Folder 54)
    - "Essais de Modification des Nuages dans les Pyrenees", 1951 June 06 (Box 19, Folder 55)
    - Fasciation (collected articles on), 1948; 1971; Undated (Box 19, Folder 56)
    - Fire Danger Meter and Burning Index Meter, 1942 April (Box 19, Folder 57)
    - Fires in Ontario- Map and Data, 1948 June (Box 19, Folder 58)
    - "A Five- Year Record of Lightning Storms and Forest Fires", H.T. Gisborne, 1931 April (Box 19, Folder 59)
    - Flashtubes- General Electric and Strobo Research, 1947-1948; Undated (Box 19, Folder 60)
    - Copy of 1752 letter on Electricity- Franklin, Benjamin, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 61)
    - General Engineering Lab Research Publications, 1955-1959 (Box 19, Folder 62)
    - Geodimeter description, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 63)
    - Groundwater Elevation in the Hudson- Mohawk Drainage Basin, 1931-1950 (Box 19, Folder 64)
    - Hailstones, 1949-1950; Undated (Box 19, Folder 65)
    - High Altitude Observatory: Contributions and Supplemental Information, 1953 March (Box 19, Folder 66)
    - High Voltage Radiography Symposium, 1952 March 04-1952 March 05 (Box 19, Folder 67)
    - Identification badge- Schaefer, General Electric, Undated (Box 19, Folder 68)
    - Incense (Blue Smoke) graph, Undated (Box 19, Folder 69)
    - Institute of Navigation Meeting Program, 1947 February 13-1947 February 14 (Box 19, Folder 70)
    - Instructions for Operating the Kodaslide Projector, Model 2A, ca. 1947 (Box 19, Folder 71)
    - Instructions: Portable and Switchboard Recording Instruments (Types CF-1, 2, 4, and 5), ca. 1950 (Box 19, Folder 72)
    - Instrumentation for Industrial Hygiene Symposium, 1954 May 24-1954 May 27 (Box 19, Folder 73)
    - Iodine Abstracts and Reviews, Vol. I #3-6 and Vol. II #1, 1950 January-1950 October; 1951 January-1951 April (Box 19, Folder 74)
    - Isotopes-Supplement #1, 1949 September (Box 19, Folder 75)
    - Japanese Article, Undated (Box 19, Folder 76)
    - Jet Stream- Radio press releases, 1953 January 26 (Box 19, Folder 77)
    - Laboratory Conference No.8- research presentations, artists rendering at the knolls, plans for research lab, 1945 October 11-1945 October 12 (Box 19, Folder 78)
    - Laboratory Study and Development Program, Undated (Box 19, Folder 79)
    - Landform Map of the Northwestern States, Copyright 1941, Undated (Box 19, Folder 80)
    - Landform Map of the United States, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 81)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Biography by A.C. Langmuir, 1932 December (Box 19, Folder 82)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Biography by K.B. Blodgett, 1933 July (Box 19, Folder 83)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Biography by W.R. Whitney, 1941 February (Box 19, Folder 84)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Biography Reprinted from Scientific American, 1937 September (Box 19, Folder 85)
    - Langmuir, Irving: "Book U" Supplements, 1952-1953 (Box 19, Folder 86)
    - Langmuir, Irving: The Collected Works of Irving Langmuir-Introduction to Volume VII by Schaefer, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 87)
    - Langmuir, Irving: The Collected Works of Irving Langmuir-Introduction to Volume 10 by Schaefer, Undated (Box 19, Folder 88)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Columbia University Engineering Center News, 1951 December (Box 19, Folder 89)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Memorial Speech by Nephews, Union College, 1957 August 21 (Box 19, Folder 90)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Memorials by Schaefer, 1957-1958 (Box 19, Folder 91)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Perkin Medal Award, 1928 (Box 19, Folder 92)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Photo album index, ca. 1950 (Box 19, Folder 93)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Portrait Photos, Undated (Box 19, Folder 94)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Portrait Photo, Undated (Oversized 4, Folder 3)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Priestley Medal Award, 1929 October (Box 19, Folder 95)
    - Langmuir, Irving: Publications list, Undated (Box 19, Folder 96)
    - Langmuir, Irving: "A Tribute to Irving Langmuir, 1881-1957", 1957 August 19 (Box 19, Folder 97)
    - Le Recueil, 1947 March (Box 19, Folder 98)
    - "Lichtstreuung an Aerosolteilchen", 1952 April (Box 19, Folder 99)
    - Map: United States Department of Agriculture Forest Service, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 100)
    - Memo: H.T. Gisborne- Use of B-29 Jets in Lightning Fire Prevention, 1949 June 29 (Box 19, Folder 101)
    - Meteorological office equipment requirements, 1952 March 06 (Box 19, Folder 102)
    - Mohawk Association of Scientists and Engineers Newsletter, 1952 August 27 (Box 19, Folder 103)
    - Mohawk Association of Scientists and Engineers Newsletter (MASE), 1953 June 17 (Box 19, Folder 104)
    - Multicell structure- official patent with original letter regarding application of invention, 1950 November 03; 1956 January 24 (Box 19, Folder 105)
    - Museum Service-Bulletin of Rochester Museum of Arts & Sciences, 1939 March; 1939 April (Box 19, Folder 106)
    - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics- Research abstracts, 1951 June 15 (Box 19, Folder 107)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1939-1950; Undated (Box 19, Folder 108)
    - New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology Catalog, 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 109)
    - New York Academy of Sciences Meetings, 1949- 1950 (Box 19, Folder 110)
    - North American Weather Consultants, 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 111)
    - Northern Rocky Mountain Forest & Range Experiment Station- List of Publications Available for Distribution of Loan, 1958 June (Box 19, Folder 112)
    - Notebook with E.E. Hubert Business card, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 113)
    - Nucleation Symposium- Industrial & Engineering Division, American Chemical Society, Undated (Box 19, Folder 114)
    - Outdoor Hobbies of Schaefer's (GE news release), ca. 1942 (Box 19, Folder 115)
    - Ozone Pollution- American Optical Company, 1953; Undated (Box 19, Folder 116)
    - Panel Discussion- "The Public Looks at the College", Undated (Box 19, Folder 117)
    - Papers and speakers- Presentations through the year, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 118)
    - Patents, 1934-1952 (Box 19, Folder 119)
    - "Petrographic Analysis of Novacite", author unidentified, Undated (Box 19, Folder 120)
    - Photo Caption cards (?), Undated (Box 19, Folder 121)
    - Photo: Einstein, Albert with unidentified group, Undated (Box 19, Folder 122)
    - Photo: "Man Makes Snow!" exhibit, Undated (Box 19, Folder 123)
    - Photo: Model "A" Microscope Illuminator, Undated (Box 19, Folder 124)
    - Photo: Pennsylvania electric Association Hydraulic Power Committee, with list of names, 1952 April (Box 19, Folder 125)
    - Photo: Portrait of Schaefer, ca. 1945 (Box 19, Folder 126)
    - Photo: Research laboratory(?), Undated (Box 19, Folder 127)
    - Photo: Schaefer and Langmuir at General Electric, ca. 1946 (Box 19, Folder 128)
    - Photo: Schaefer with unidentified colleagues, Undated (Box 19, Folder 129)
    - Photo: Schenectady and Glenmont, Aerial View, 1944 December 29 (Box 19, Folder 130)
    - Photo: School Science fair (weather station), Undated (Box 19, Folder 131)
    - Photo: Schoon, Alexander-"Class of 1931", Undated (Box 19, Folder 132)
    - Photo: Woman Reading Boston Globe Story on Schaefer's First Successful Cloud Seeding, ca. November 1946 (Box 19, Folder 133)
    - Photographic Data Kodachrome Professional Set Film-List, 1943 July (Box 19, Folder 134)
    - Photos: Dr. C. Guy Suits and General Electric Research Laboratory, Undated (Box 19, Folder 135)
    - Photos: Equipment, Schaefer and Colleagues, Unidentified Experiments, 1940; Undated (Box 19, Folder 136)
    - Photos: Lab instruments, 1945 August 11; 1945 September 10 (Box 19, Folder 137)
    - Photos: Langmuir, I., 1910; 1935; Undated (Box 19, Folder 138)
    - Photos: Mount Cimone and unidentified, Undated (Box 19, Folder 139)
    - Photos: New York State Barge Canal, Aerial Views, Likely Schenectady Area, 1935 October 26; Undated (Box 19, Folder 140)
    - Photos: New York State Barge Canal, Aerial Views, Likely Schenectady Area, 1941 April 23; Undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Photos: New York State Barge Canal, Aerial Views, Likely Schenectady Area, Undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Photos: Schaefer Alone, with Colleagues, and with Family, ca. 1930-c.1970 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Photos: Schaefer and unidentified men, possibly at Crater Lake, 1947 June 20 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Photos: Science Forum Panel First Meeting, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Photos: Scientific instruments, Undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Photos: Smoke generator assembly (with key to identify parts), 1942 March 13 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Photos: Unidentified (includes negatives), 1949 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Photos: Unidentified subjects, Undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Physics Today, 1948 August (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Porous Vycor Glass shipping memorandum, 1952 January 31 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Postcard from Mexico, Undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Press Release: "High School Girl Constructs Snowmaking Device for $4.32", 1947 June 27 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Press Release: "Oil Drops Assume Geometrical Shapes on Protein Films", with photo, Undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Priest River Photos, 1948 August (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Program for Appliance and Merchandise Department, 1951 March 13 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Programs: American Meteorological Society 102nd National Meting with 30th Annual Meeting of American Geophysical Union, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Project Jupiter- Conference at Schenectady, list of names, 1952 November 14 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Publicity Department Photos (includes electron microscope images), 1943 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Radiosonde and Rawinsonde Stations in the U.S, Undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Rain Forest, 1953 June (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Raindrop Physics Study Proposal, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Report Recipients Checklist (report unspecified), Undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Research Laboratory Bulletins, 1947; 1949; Undated (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Research Laboratory- Ceremony of Dedication Program, 1950 October 09 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Research laboratory: "Current Research Activities", 1948 October 01 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Research Laboratory: History by I. Langmuir and others, manuscript, Undated (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Research laboratory: Request for project summary, 1947 April 01 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Research Laboratory: Shop Order requests, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Research Laboratory: Time Clock Requirement Memo, 1938 June 17 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Research Site Map, Undated (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Reviews by Schaefer and Others, 1940; 1980 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Robert M. Losey Award to Schaefer- Press Release, 1953 January 20 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Roche Research Club Program, 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Rochester Museum Council- Fellowship to Schaefer, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Royal Meteorological Society- Centenary materials, charter and by-laws handbook, 1948; 1950 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Royal Meteorological Society- Centenary meeting: correspondence, brochure, & supplemental materials, 1949-1950 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Salt: The Story of Diamond Crystal Salt, Undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Schaefer Statements on Weather Modification with Unidentified "Council Letters", 1951 June 08; 1953 February-1953 March; Undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Schaefer Statement Prepared for Senator James P. Kem- Kansas-Missouri Floods, Undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Schaefer with unidentified colleagues, Ottawa- photo, 1949 Fall (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Schenectady Plant- Visits, 1949; 1952 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Schenectady Works Apprentice Alumni Association-Book and Photograph, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Science: Vol.89, #2316, 1939 May 19 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Science Service (Scientific News Reports), 1946-1948; 1952 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Scientific Conferences, 1950-1951; Undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Severe Storms Report- University of Chicago, 1950 July (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Shell Aviation News, Issue #180(Schaefer on pp. 4-6), 1953 June (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "Sketches of Dr. Langmuir and Dr. Whitney", With Additional Drawings and Notes by V. Schaefer, 1934-1935; Undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Smoke Generation- Article in Popular Science, 1943 July (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Snowflake Preservation and Replica Posters, Undated (Oversized 2, Folder 1)
    - "Snowflake Scientist" Cartoon from Young Catholic Messenger, 1951 November 23 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - "Some Questions Science Does Not Answer", Dr. Harold A. Larrabee- Talk Delivered in G.E.'s "Science Forum" Radio Program, 1951 April 04 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Speech: "Planning Unplanned Research", Research laboratory Colloquium, I. Langmuir, 1951 December 12 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Speech: "Progress in Control of Meteorological Factors", V.J. Schaefer, 1952 April (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Surface Replicas: "Snowflake Hobby Leads to New Way of Studying War Metals", 1942 May; 1942 June (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Symposium on Nucleation- Program and Paper Abstracts, 1951 December 27-1951 December 28 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Talks: American Chemical Society (Wooster College section), 1949 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Talks: Eastern Colleges Science Conference, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Talks: "Farm Forum" (WGY) "Doing Something About the Weather", 1947 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Talks: The Franklin Institute, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Talks: Friends of the Land, 1951 June 21 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Talks: Hanford Engineer Works (Hanford, WA), 1947 April 19 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Talks: Institute of Navigation, 1947 February 13-1947 February 14 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Talks: The Johns Hopkins Research Conference, Undated (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Talks: Kiwanis Club of Gloversville, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Talks: Kiwanis Club of Rotterdam, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Talks: Lake Pleasant Central School (Speculator, NY), 1948 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Talks: New Mexico Wool Growers Association, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Talks: New York Railroad Club, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Talks: New York University, 1953 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Talks: Pittsfield, MA Chamber of Commerce, Undated (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Talks: The Rensselaer Physical Society, 1948 April 27 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Talks: Rotary Club of Schenectady, 1947 January 01-1947 January 16 (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Talks: "Science Forum" (WGY), 1947 April 09 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Talks: Education Board Conference (Program), 1947 (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Talks: Sigma Xi, 1948 March 27 (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - Talks: Sigma Xi- Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn Chapter, 1948 May 20 (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - Talks: Union College Physics Society, 1951 November 07 (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - Talks: University of Delaware, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 43)
    - Talks: Western Forestry and Conservation Association, 1952 December 11 (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - Technical Development Committee- Symposium on Polar Navigation, 1946 December 16-1946 December 20 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Text Proposed for Guest Column of Mr. Robert S. Allen, Post-Hall Newspaper Syndicate (By V.J. Schaefer), 1953 August 07 (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - Thunderstorm Electricity Conference- Advance Materials, 1950 March (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Topical Organization of First National Conference on the Electron Microscope, 1942 November 27 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Tribute to Schaefer-Research Laboratory Memo, 1948 May (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Trurnit, Hans J. (M.D.)- Bibliography, Undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture Circular #591: Influence of Altitude and Aspect on Daily Variations in Factors of Forest-Fire Danger, 1941 February (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Military Map, Undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "Unforeseeable Results of Research," I. Langmuir- Radio Broadcast, 1945 January 21 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Union Geodesique et Geophysique Internationale Association de Meteorologie, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - United Nations Scientific Conference on the Conservation and Utilization of Resources, 1949 April 22 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Vocational Training Record Card for V. Schaefer (National Defense), 1941 December 22 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - "We the People" Radio Script Featuring V.J. Schaefer, 1947 January 19 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - "Weather as a Natural Resource"- Proposed Script for Radio Talk, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Weather! Bulletin of the National Weather Improvement Association, 1951 August 30; 1951 September 07 (Box 22, Folder 13)